Hey. Marcus.
You have to register with both name and ID.
You're not allowed to film anymore.
For my part, it would be okay, but it must be approved by my boss.
We have reached the end of our experiment where four hackers–
- attacks people and companies to show how vulnerable we are.
We know that foreign powers have stolen information from Swedish authorities.
In this episode the security will be tested at Telenor.
It's a critical infrastructure that foreign power wants control over.
There's a large flow of information.
It will be the largest company we attack. A huge challenge.
Can the hackers navigate past advanced security systems -
- and a large team that only exist to catch them?
This is one of our crisis rooms.
This is where we will have the exercise.
-What computers will we get? -These are our client computers.
The hackers will act as agents from foreign power.
Telenor has advanced monitoring -
-And conduct regular simulated attacks to find weaknesses.
The hackers have received an office computer -
- which corresponds to the ones used by company employees.
They need to navigate as quietly as possible through the huge network -
-To find a path to servers with sensitive information.
A major challenge with the assignment is that the company’s own security team
-Which is called Blue team, constantly scans the network for attackers.
That is what we have against us during these hours.
The idea is that security should be as normal as possible.
My primary responsibility is to ensure that the technology works.
Also make sure that they don't break anything.
Whatever we poke at there are sensors there?
Yes.
It's not easy.
It will be a challenge.
It will be difficult, I think so.
We have many limitations and little time.
We have two days, maybe 30 hours if we don't sleep.
Very bad conditions for us to succeed.
There has been a lot of preparation, many meetings–
-Where we've discussed both the exercise and all legislation.
We have signed agreements, at least two.
There are so many rules.
If they don't follow them, we'll kick them out.
All offensive decisions we must take together.
They have to go through the exercise leaders.
To sit there on a system that is incredibly large–
- with many limitations, computers that are not even your own
- and a process that makes you have to get everything approved by a dungeon master ...
Do you feel ready, and have everything you need?
-I think so. -Perfect, then we'll start the exercise.
Let's take these off.
So should I look at storage space on the network?
Including databases.
- You'll go for accounts. -Everything with AD, at a slow pace.
–Webb. -Everything like that.
To avoid making noise -
it'll be good if we can look for things which can give us more.
Now we need to figure out how the network looks like-
- without showing the Blue team that we're here–
And find the networks that aren't forbidden, and attack them.
Tele companies are equally important as bridges, roads, harbors.
An attack on a large tele company can seriously disrupt–
society's ability to function.
Customer information, calls ... Everything - text messages and stuff.
All that information is very sensitive -
-And is fantastic for us as a foreign power to access.
Just that people use SMS to log in to accounts ...
If we can then take over arbitrary phone numbers, we can access
-Many people's accounts.
We've got these hackers here, who are among the better in Sweden.
How do they think? What tactics and what tools do they use?
And how do they do it? It's most interesting.
They don't know that our plan is to suck out their knowledge.
Ulf Andersson works as information security manager–
-But has its background in the intelligence service and Säpo.
He brings with him his experiences into the job of IT security.
In my team we have hackers–
-But if you add intelligence- background, to really understand
- what intelligence is all about, how you work to get information ...
To translate it into this field, I think gives a great advantage.
Because everything is about obtaining information.
The one who has most information will win, history has proven.
Stig Wennerström, one of Sweden's most famous spies–
- is arrested and brought to justice in 1963, after 20 years of reconnaissance work.
In his home there's photographic equipment and microfilms with documents
- which Wennerström photographed and sent to the Soviet Union.
But today the spies are sitting in front of the computer.
The cyber attacks from foreign powers are so frequent and intense–
- that they are on the border between espionage and low-intensity warfare.
The US president warned this spring for the consequences of the development.
The threat to Sweden in the form of cyber attacks from foreign powers
- are real.
We see how the threats have expanded and deepened over a number of years.
The consequences are serious. It's for real - they're real people.
It takes place daily against Sweden from a variety of countries.
We see how foreign power comes in and steals research, development -
-blueprints - entire production environments, to bring home to their countries.
The countries that pose the greatest threat are Russia, China and Iran.
Today it's an uneven match. Those who attack us have a head start.
Not much resources are invested in security, which would be needed
- considering the threat. There are great values at stake.
It's not just computer stuff, the consequences can be serious.
They can affect the financial foundations of Sweden's democracy.
-How's it going? - The technology is up and running.
So they will probably have a lot to do. Absolutely.
I talked to the Blue team, they got the starting signal at the same time.
Okay.
Then they'll soon be discovered.
Yes. We'll see, it hasn't been that long.
10 62.
Is it also forbidden? Everything is forbidden.
We had a list of systems which we weren't allowed to touch.
On that list, they added more and more.
The more we found, the more they realized: "No, by the way, don't touch it."
We suggested several attacks.
Each attack must be approved, so we had to wait a lot.
It's so frustrating!
Our core network has all the info.
This is where our secret databases are located, with all customer data.
That's where you want to go when talking telecommunications.
They were not allowed to go there. We had  limits on what they were allowed to do.
We knew that if they go there-
- functions could break down, and we would have a lot of problems.
It became messy. Everyone tried to be creative and come up with good ideas.
This is half joke, half serious. Let's buy a botnet.
Nuke some service from the outside... No, but listen. Hear me out!
Basically three kids in a candy store.
Normally when we do this, it's "free for all", just to pick and attack.
You lost me when you said: "Buy a botnet."
In the end, we ignored the alarms and just rolled with it.
"We're getting nowhere," because everything was forbidden. We did everything we could.
To navigate the huge network they need to do a scan -
-On over 4,000 IP addresses.
The problem is that it generates a lot of traffic. They risk detection.
We'll ignore the Blue team. We're hoping they look at China.
If they don't detect us now, they're real losers. We'll assume they will.
Three ... two ... one ...
Blue team - now they'll stop drinking coffee.
There was a lot of traffic which was pushed through. Very obvious.
All their logs lit up like a Christmas tree, probably.
-Hello. -Hey.
-How's it going? -To hell.
A cat and rat game. You should never accept that a foreign power is inside.
No other technical problems which we need to sort out?
No.
I have contact with the Blue team internally.
They get no info what is happening on the other side. I'll look up what they find.
Yes.... Yes?
I checked with the Blue team. It was actually very comical ...
They said it sounded like a tank drove around the infrastructure.
They are THAT noisy?
In a realistic scenario, we would have stopped them immediately.
After a few minutes or so.
But then there wont be an exercise. What do you learn from stopping it?
It's better to open the door and see what they'll do.
Give me five minutes.
-Should I run a hydra from our C2? -Yes. Take one at a time.
Check.
We asked Marcus: "May we look at other parts of the network? "
We got to look at some other systems.
On them, Jinny found an encrypted password.
Actually, we found 26 encrypted passwords.
But one of them we managed to crack with a simple dictionary.
We have found a machine which we can access.
It had a folder that we can read.
Tt looks like there are folders which appears to belong to users.
Maybe all users, even. We can read them and watch the content.
If an administrator has saved their password in their profile.
Then we have it and maybe can jump to other machines.
Take over machines, quite simply. Jump on to the more sensitive resources.
What Linus is doing now is to copy over all content–
-To a USB stick, so that we get access to all that information.
Even if the Blue team sees this ...
We don't care. We just want to get the info as fast as possible.
We'll barricade that door, so that they can't break in.
That's what we're doing right now. It's the first really interesting finding.
It could be a gold mine.
I think... There has been a shift.
Private companies, especially the telco companies -
-Have realized that they are socially critical infrastructure.
They are the key for society to work. Everything is based on communication.
That awakening has probably happened since x number of years back.
If the communication stops working, society is likely to collapse.
Then we can't communicate. We are so used to the phone constantly working.
That's the big awakening among telecom companies.
To realize that we are so important to society.
Many cyber attacks have been linked to foreign power.
This applies to attacks on waterworks, food manufacturers -
-Fuel companies and authorities.
The US administration accuses Russia
-To allow hacker groups to act freely, without intervening.
Biden has proposed an agreement which protects critical infrastructure.
We are used to battles between countries being conducted militarily.
But thanks to technological development and development of cyber tools -
- much of the struggle has been moved to the cyber domains or the cyber world.
That's where it takes place a struggle between countries.
It's not as visible.
You may not always know who fires the digital shots.
Which makes the security environment has become more difficult to understand.
You have to take security seriously.
One must take the ability of a foreign power to conduct such business seriously.
These are people in other countries who have a salary–
-To conduct that type of activities - government officials.
There are companies that have been unaware that they have had an IT intrusion.
They have become aware of it only when we contacted them–
-Or when they see a copy of their product in another country.
That's because those countries have big resources and are technically proficient.
If they meet a Swedish company who do not have a high level of protection
- it will be an easy prey.
IT security will become even more important.
In the future, we will be more connected.
Launch of 5G, which is coming, means that we become even more connected.
The cars will be connected.
Everything from refrigerators to whatever you can imagine, will be connected.
There will always be vulnerabilities, so people need to be more prepared–
-And test themselves.
It is about who finds the vulnerabilities first, we or the opponent?
Then it's better to try to find the vulnerabilities yourself.
Get help from anyone who can help.
Continue to find your own vulnerabilities.
I have found a lot of systems that are super interesting - old stuff.
We can always get in there.
Blue team seems to have seen that you made weird connections to the Internet.
That they want an explanation for.
- Against the internet? -Yes, some port 22.
It was against your address.
We're downloading a "wordlist" to crack hashes.
Yes.
- Did you talk to a colleague? - We haven't spoken to anyone on the phone.
-So you got no help? No.
We found quite a lot of interesting stuff.
27 minutes left, and we've cracked a hash.
We have a hash. We have that password.
That was interesting. Really good.
Yes, Jinny is testing if she can login with it.
I feel that Marcus became quite nervous when he saw the account.
We asked for a "ticket". Then we cracked it.
But how did you find the service?
- We asked ... -You ran that ... what's it called?
Get-SPN. We've found a lot of fun. stuff.
We are now decrypting this.
These are saved passwords in a Chrome session.
We've got a lot of Chrome files from these profiles.
In the vhd files, someone has saved passwords in the browser.
Username "Admin", to all of these addresses.
We don't have the password yet, but looking at it.
We've also gotten in here.
It's a Wiki ... Maybe shouldn't film it before he says okay.
I created an account. I was allowed to create an account -
-And I've read a lot of interesting stuff.
-It's interesting. -Yes it is.
The wiki server contained information -
-Which can be seen as a kind of map over parts of the network.
We haven't had time to analyze the material.
It seems to be username and passwords to other parts of the network -
- which isn't good at all. That is the risk we must address.
We found an account ... You seem to want to do something.
Now we have a hash we have to crack. If it works, we can decrypt them ...
- Where did you get that hash from? -Magic.
I searched for the password, and then I read. Do you have to kill me now?
Yes.
No, so ... Is the camera off?
-What has happened now? - They have discovered ...
... that they could retrieve passwords from internal services.
-Food! - Wonderful!
The next directive is that as soon as the Blue team thinks that this-
-Can risk our services, then we cancel.
We went from practice mode to incident mode where all teams are activated.
You may notify the hackers to stop.
Hi. Could you pause everything and come with me?
We'll have an incident meeting. It's important that we do it now.
-Come, we need to fix this. -You look so serious.
Can we turn off the camera and tell us what we aren't allowed to do?
It is "no go zone".
Shall we gather?
Good. - Thank you, Marcus.
We had to take a short break and stop the exercise a bit.
You were supposed to find things.
That's why we joined this game. And now you have done it.
It's really fantastic. But what you have found, must be fixed.
And it's pretty urgent. We have started the incident process.
Because what you found ... I can't say where you would have ended up–
-But we value it as a major vulnerability.
So I find it difficult to continue the exercise.
But at the same time I'm incredibly grateful –
- that you have found it.
Somehow I'm glad that we could do this together.
I'm trying to convey a joy here.
But also a concern, because we have to fix it.
If a real opponent found it, it would have major consequences.
Shall we continue the exercise or fix the vulnerability?
The choice was pretty easy for me. I quickly realized:
"Now it's serious, now we can't discuss viewer numbers. "
Thanks! Totally fantastic that you found the vulnerability.
A bit frustrating. I guess this is how to end an exercise-
-When you find something really juicy, which makes us even better.
So super-thank you.
The hackers were discovered early and did not reach the sensitive servers.
However, they found vulnerabilities that got Telenor to cancel the exercise -
-To initiate incident management.
It turned out that the information didn't lead to critical data.
The risk is still greater if you don't do this.
"If we don't do this, we'll still get greater risks, because then we know nothing. "
Knowing nothing is the biggest risk.
We live in a digital society–
- where our assets online are as real as the physical ones.
The hackers have shown how easy it is to gain access to individuals and companies.
It's time to take your digital life seriously.
I think we will be able to handle information like we've always done.
It takes time, and things will happen.
But they had the same discussion about the telegraph - it was dangerous.
The radio was dangerous. We're not even going to talk about TV.
I see a bright future.
In 20-30 years, I think we'll have adapted to digitalisation.
To be afraid of such activities is not something you gain on.
We advocate sound vigilance.
To have the radar up and keep track of your surroundings.
This competence must be taught as early as possible - in preschool -
-In primary school, in high school and also in higher education.
Because this is important to learn.
Subtitles: Johan Johansson Swedish Media Text for SVT