"Let's do this."
-Should this be on? Yeah, think so?
I record all calls, so we have extra backup if this gives up.
A large part of crime has moved online:
Everything from simple, small scams to serious organized crime.
Oh yeah. These are the awesome. They look good. These are our cameras.
It's no longer teenagers who do things just because you can–
- but criminal elements.
This is also a camera. I'm so equipped now.
The security company Gunnebo has been attacked.
Is the camera running?
So I don't go in, and then just ... panic.
SVT has let four professional hackers attack individuals–
and companies, to show how vulnerable we are in our connected society.
Organized crime has moved online.
Coop had to close almost all of its 800 stores.
Serious cyberattacks increases every year–
And huge ransoms are paid to save companies from ruin.
Can our hackers access big business via a secret shortcut?
/ CALL SIGNAL /
I'm terrified they'll be suspicious and call the police.
are you nervous, Jinny?
Our hackers are playing criminals.
In two days they have to infiltrate the IT company Langate.
Jesper and Jinny are using Social manipulation,
- to be let in to the company to gain a foothold.
No one there, except the CEO, knows about the hack.
Jinny is dressed as a worker and will say she has to check humidity.
They have made a "cover story" where her name is Frida.
They have a website for Flexvatten, the company she's from.
I'll park here. It's good if we're not seen.
- We can stop here. -Yeah, thinking about that too.
The risk is they'll call the police.
That they catch you, become suspicious and keep you there.
In reality, this had been a fairly serious crime.
Anyone who wants to attack several companies can target a supplier -
- a so-called supply chain attack.
Langate is small with many customers. If the hackers manage to infiltrate them–
- then the opportunity to access a large number of companies is opened.
The last few meters ... I didn't check the heart monitor, but it was probably high.
I got really nervous.
Hey! I'm here to measure some moisture in your walls.
- From Sölvesborgs Construction, or? -Yes. Or from Sölvesborg municipality.
Is it okay?
We humans have a tendency to fill in the blanks -
-If someone seems to fit in a role.
If you look like an IT technician, then you probably are.
-Where do you the kitchen and ...? - The kitchen is in there.
-Bathroom? -There.
If you look like you belong in an environment, we assume you do.
We may not stop a person and ask to see the ID -
-Or look closely and realize that the ID is fake.
The world's thickest wall is useless if someone opens a door in it.
I looked for cables in the ceiling and for a cable to a TV
-But there was nothing, so we concluded that they ran everything on wifi.
And we had not prepped for that.
She's been inside for 15 minutes so far.
I felt that I had to go one more round.
Then I saw a door. I went straight in as if I knew what was there.
There was a switch - network equipment - and some type of server
-With lights flashing.
So it was a gold mine, just what I were looking for.
Fast as hell, take up everything, plug in, plug in power ...
Jinny?
Something is happening.
Out through door and pretend to write. I wrote on the paper all the way out.
- Did you go out, Jinny? -Yes.
Did you plug it in? Do you know that you got a link?
- It flashed. - It hasn't come up yet.
Forget it. It came up! It's up. Yes, we have contact!
Holy shit!
Oh! How fucking nervous I was.
So fucking good!
Like, fuck.
The glasses were foggy all the time.
She's a fucking hero. I'm on a parking lot, so I'll pull away.
Feel free to start Responder in analyze mode, right away.
There's a risk that he ... When I said what wanted to do, he paused.
It feels like I've done something bad, and we have.
At the end of 2020 there was a major supply chain attack
- against the security company Solarwinds.
In the attack, malicious code was spread to Solarwind's customers -
–For instance the US military and several other security companies.
In Sweden, e.g. Volvo Cars, Skanska and Space Agency.
The US Treasury Department pointed out Russia as responsible for the attack.
I'm so fucking ... almost vomiting now,  ... of adrenaline.
How do we start the conversation? Only: "Hello, we want to hack your business."
While Linus is investigating the company from the inside -
- they meet with the company's CEO to discuss the assignment.
The CEO does not know that the hackers have jumpstarted.
- Wanna have lunch and talk? -Yes, we should do that.
Nobody at Langate knows this.
No one on the staff, no one knows that this will be done.
I do not know the details myself, but now I'm going to be hacked.
"Good luck." But not too much "luck".
We at Langate know that we may be the victim of a hacker attack -
-To access our customers.
- We want to create as good protection as we can. -Because you become the most sensitive part.
Yes, we will be the service provider supply chain to others.
Potentially, one could reach–
-About a hundred customers important information.
-Or make do ransomware attack ... -Some kind of malicious code.
Or just access information that you see has an incredible business value.
I had an experience this weekend. A customer who has refused protection -
-And insist that we publish our terminal server.
Then they got ransomware, and boom the pay system stopped working. Nasty!
Ransomware is a billion dollar industry. It will only get bigger.
Swedish companies that are attacked by ransomware and pays ...
The total amount per year amounts to several billion SEK.
There are cases where Swedish companies has paid close to 300 million–
-To get their files unlocked. And that is ONE company.
A hacker who accessed resources can perform a ransomware attack.
What happens is that all files are encrypted and locked.
Now a key is required to restore everything.
The files were hijacked by the hacker, who demands money to unlock.
The Coop food chain had to close almost all of its 800 stores.
-After the cash register system failed.
This summer, Coop was hit by a ransomware attack-
-Which was also a supply chain attack.
Operation of Coop's cash register system is handled by the company Visma Esscom.
Visma in turn uses services from the company Kaseya.
It was Kaseya who was attacked by a hacker.
The malicious code was spread to Visma and caused Coop's cash registers to be locked.
Coop had to close 800 stores while they restarted all cash registers manually.
There are more examples of attacks which affected companies and infrastructure.
2019 the aluminium manufacturer Norsk Hydro was affected.
It was enough for an employee to click on a link in an email.
The hackers entered Hydro's IT environment and planted a virus–
-Which they used to encrypt information throughout the company.
Computers and servers were locked and production lines stopped.
The total sum for the attack estimated at $ 75 million.
Norsk Hydro never paid any ransom.
They had backups on their data and was able to restart operations.
Sensitive information about bank vaults, alarms systems and the government is online.
The security company Gunnebo was hit by a ransomware attack in 2020.
Gunnebo refused to pay the ransom. About 38,000 documents were leaked -
and are exposed online.
drawings of bank vaults, alarm systems and sensitive facilities.
In a survey among 150 IT-managers at Swedish companies -
- 30% state that they've been exposed to one ransomware attack in the last year.
Here we go. Let's do it.
-Now we're on our way. How nice! -It's fun to watch it.
Hey! I'm here to measure some moisture in your walls.
- From Sölvesborgs Construction, or? -Yes. Or from Sölvesborg municipality.
I checked under the sink and so on.
- Moist tile, then?. -Yeah, what the hell do I know?
In an attack like this, you don't know how prepared the victim is.
So you need to do it slowly and carefully, so that you do not ...
You don't want to make too much noise in the network.
You don't know what to expect. It's a bit like a maze without a map.
You have a bunch of cool tools, but there are monsters in the maze.
- No password spraying, just. -No no no.
Come on...! I Having some issues here.
We start to map out what is there. We clearly see people going home.
We have no success. The attacks which we normally use do not work.
I'm wondering if we should test–
-to do an active Responder on ONE computer.
-They have a lot of different things. - That's what I'm looking at.
I can't take it. I have to sleep.
We have a program which will run overnight–
-And when they come to the office tomorrow.
Hopefully someone has a laptop with them that they had brought home.
When they start it, it will hopefully trigger something that we can catch.
There is a reason to stay late.
You can do bolder things on the network -
- without worrying about people noticing it.
So there is every reason to stay late.
Ransomware attacks are common, but a crime that few want to talk about.
SVT has asked several companies subjected to major attacks -
- but none of them want to line up for an interview.
Nobody knows how common it is–
-Because companies do not report it to the police.
It may be that they think that the police will do nothing -
-Or that you do not want to broadcast that you have had an attack -
-Which has hit hard, because companies think it would mean-
-That "we show that we have bad security and get no customers ".
We have to be a bit more structured now.
- For Responder ... -Responder has no hits.
When we arrived today, nothing had happened.
We have to reach all these customers, that's the goal.
We need to access a machine, the backup server ...
We need to reach customers.
They may very well have some tech nerd who've made sure they are safe.
It's a disaster for us. Then we have to get very creative.
In the worst case you had a good idea there, Linus.
Trying to poison the network and force a machine to connect to us.
Maybe we should perform a bolder attack anyway.
With bolder I mean: If we're looking for something in a forest
- then we'll blow away all the trees to find something on the ground.
Jesper's attack will possibly stop the network from working -
-For the ones we attack.
Our tiny computer, which we have hidden behind a cupboard inside the company ...
We decided to tunnel all traffic through this little point–
-To force everything that is sitting in the network to do what we want.
Nobody remembers a coward. Shall we press all three?
-Shared responsibility is not responsibility. - You have full power.
I'll press now, then.
It's running.
Yes! New hash. Damn, what a treat.
Come on now!
It will be seen, this is noisy.
Yes, and it does.
–Oh, oh. - What?
- Have you found a net? Min session är nere.
-No no no....
They found it?
After a while our terminal freeze–
- and we lose the connection to our unit that sits on the inside.
Yes, I'm all out.
- Damn. We were too aggressive. -Yes, you can probably say that.
They find our box and disconnect it. We lose the connection. Game over.
Now that we are blind again and have no access, we have a few hashes.
The hashes are the cryptographic equivalent of a password.
And we can crack these using computing power.
Powerful computers with graphics cards which we ask to solve our problem.
Time is running out. While Linus is trying to crack passwords
- Jinny and Jesper go back to the company office.
It's time to reveal ourselves.
We'll see what they answer, if they have noticed anything.
-Welcome! -Thank you. - After you.
-Are you having a good time? -Yes.
We have some friends with us, me and my colleague:
Jinny, or Frida.
We work as IT security experts.
We have been doing some stuff with you.
It's silence. Everything has been good? The week has been good?
No disturbances?
My feeling when these two people came in:
"Wow, now he's hired an entertainment group "-
- "which will entertain us." They said they were IT experts.
So I'm thinking: "Yes, now there will be a lot of IT jokes, because that's our thing. "
Anyone recognize my colleague here?
-Yes! No, what the hell ... - You should recognize me.
Oh, what the hell is that ...? Ah! Okay!
Then I recognize Jinny, who has infiltrated us.
I'm the one who opens the door.
Hey! I'm here to measure some moisture in your walls.
-What did we do here, quite simply? -You were measuring moi ...
It was a very positive reaction. I was afraid he would get angry.
But he laughed and ... So there's shock, but laughter, as well.
I'm in a call when I open the door. I'm talking to a customer about security.
I say, "The doorbell rings."
"Hi, my name is Frida I'm going to measure moisture. "-" Yes, go ahead. "
"It's very important, with security! "
But you haven't noticed anything on infrastructure or ...?
We noticed a response on the computer, which did not feel natural.
What's supposed to happen doesn't happen–
- instead we get a  login box. That's weird.
We have seen a small box in a room which you may have put there.
I suspect that it's no longer connected.
-How did you find it? -A colleague of mine saw it.
In reality, one of our customers was attacked for real.
So Jörgen and I request  people to come here, and tell them:
"Now we have prio 1 alert. Someone has been hacked. "
Pretty strange, weird timing.
They had another incident at the same time.
A customer had an intrusion while we were doing stuff.
"I see a box. Do you know anything about it?"
"No. No idea what internal project is this? "
"Then I want to disconnect it."
We could have stayed in the network longer if they did not have the incident.
So that was just unfortunate.
People have lost three years of work because they've been attacked.
They attacked the data, but also the backup of the data. Then it's gone.
Then you cry for real. You've worked for three years–
-for nothing and have to start over.
There is nothing to recreate or save.
We have taken two passwords and given them to our machines.
They're cracking the password still. It's not cracked yet.
We have had a very short time - we have spent almost two days on planning.
It's just a matter of time before this gets cracked.
We got our hands on two encrypted passwords - hashes.
We have tried to crack them for 24 hours and have not succeeded yet.
It's sad for us, but a good grade for Langate.
In my world you have succeeded, even if you don't think so.
The hackers managed to infiltrate the IT company–
-And had access to their network for over a day.
They could not get past the company's security system -
-And therefore could not access the customers in the network.
The passwords that the hackers came across kept good quality.
Attempts to crack them were discontinued after 48 hours.
They remain unresolved.
If I were an evil hacker, I'd be quieter–
- and take my time. When I had enough customers -
- I'd probably encrypt everything–
-And requested loads of money in ransom.
If they don't pay, yeah, go bankrupt, then.
"What do I care? I'm evil."
We currently don't have a basic level of security -
-So that we have a fairly high bar. The higher the bar is–
-The more costly and time consuming it is for an attacker-
- to try to access the information. This is business-critical.
This is what boards should be accustomed to dealing with.
You see investments in security as a cost.
If you see it as an investment, something that gives a return–
-it's easier to argue for. It's about the company's survival.
This has to end now. I'm tired of talking to desperate people -
-who get in trouble because of hacker attacks all the time.
Good morning, Klara. Hope you have slept well. Today it's sunny outside.
This so-called IoT man is like a damn mad scientist.
I'm safe, they're not getting in.
-Check if you get access. -It's up, we're in.