The time now is 09.08. - Anders!
The time now is 09.08, I'm now putting on the first product.
Linus found her downtown and pretended to be a fan of some sort–
- and wanted a selfie.
Excuse me. Therese Lindgren? My daughter watches you on Youtube.
- Can I take a selfie? -Of course.
People tend to lower their guard a bit when it comes to children.
It's a nasty tactic, but that's how it is online. There are no rules there.
What does the CEO say about how to protect yourself online?
You have a password and double password.
-He should have had triple passwords! -Hope he has.
And do you know what their password was?
I'm not joking. They had Password01.
I love "Svenska Nyheter", so it was fun to hit back.
SVT is letting professionals  hack individuals and companies -
-To show the vulnerabilities in our society.
David, Linus, Jesper and Jinny got 48 hours to hack–
- two public figures: The influencer Therese Lindgren–
And the host Kristoffer Appelquist.
To infiltrate and hijack their largest and most important online accounts.
Password01 ... I wonder if the experts believe–
- that there really is criminal superminds behind this.
But the government need help with keeping IT security at a reasonable level.
We've been looking at his online footprint.
We've looked in leaked databases and found some passwords.
Probably old passwords to old accounts that leaked.
We checked his sites online.
Often people are already hacked without knowing about it.
There are loads of information for sale on the Internet.
For instance, your address or password to your email is for sale.
They are incredibly cheap to buy, so you can buy millions of them.
Then if I choose you, I can try the password–
- since many people reuse the same password in several places.
It's mainly two passwords he's very in love with.
- He's not a mastermind of passwords? -No.
"Katamaran" has been used more than once. Then the best password–
-Which makes you like him: "hatasj". He's probably commuted a lot.
It's quite frustrating, because we have tested the passwords we found.
Nothing works. Linus and I have coded a cool thing.
But it requires access to the computer.
We must somehow deliver some form of code, a back door.
We need access to a device on his computer.
It should work. We wont fail.
Lots of people here now. We NEED to get access to his laptop.
We can't do it from the outside in the time we have.
-Yes ... It's cheating, but ... -Yeah, but you ask us to do magic.
We get so little time to do something that takes a hell of a long time.
When you're fishing for peoples password-
-you send 10 000 emails. Eventually someone takes the bait.
Here you ask us to go in and just ... / FINGER SNAP /
-It's not possible. -If we get him away from the computer ...
It's a classic thing that people do, they leave their computer unlocked.
Kristoffer has approved to be hacked.
The only thing he knows is that it will take place in the next few weeks–
- and that he will be interviewed by SVT.
I'll join you. I'll borrow a camera. I don't know how it works, but ...
I'm from Gothenburg, It'll be fine. The only cheat we're asking for ...
... is access to the computer for a minute.
You get to join us, and if you can do stuff with his computer you get to do it.
I'm reading comments. I'm looking for...
... language and words I can use in a phishing email.
Phishing is when you email and claim to be someone–
-And then tries to trick the recipient run a file or click on a link -
-Where they may need to log in with a password or similar.
Our new identity is Frida Kvarnesson.
I don't even know if it's a real name, now it is anyway.
We have all this material to create this character -
-and hopefully get Therese into a false sense of security -
- that it's a child and not someone who can hurt her.
We hope it increases the chance that she gives us her login information.
It's uncomfortable for me to log in with my index finger. Just a thing like that.
I started a makeup channel on Youtube, but only after a year–
- I started to mention that I was suffering from panic disorder.
Then I got a lot of questions about mental illness and personal issues.
I then changed my content a bit to what the people watching my videos–
- were interested in. It suited me much better too.
Today it's a lifestyle channel. I record my days.
Today there's one million followers both on Youtube and Instagram.
I'm really a control freak, so it feels uncomfortable that I'm ...
... not really in control over the technical.
Should my Youtube channel vanish because someone hacks it-
-Or whatever can happen online, then I don't know what I'll do.
I don't have a number for Youtube that can solve it. It's scary.
I'm very vulnerable. Every day I get SMS from Snapchat, Instagram ...
... and Facebook, which says: "This is the code to enter."
A two-step verification. So many people trying to get into my accounts.
But so far I have never been hacked.
"Hey, Tessan!"
"My dad met you downtown."
We can "slam" a heart emoji here.
Hopefully she'll click on the link -
And comes to a login page for her Youtube account -
- that we have created - a fake page. She's asked to log in to Youtube.
Hopefully she doesn't think twice and enters her information.
Then we'll have it and can log in to her Youtube.
I think I'm pretty reserved. It'll probably backfire.
But I don't save my passwords so that they are auto-filled.
When I enter credit card numbers -
-It asks if I want to save it, but I always press no.
I usually turn off location services on apps.
I still think about it a bit, compared to my partner who just pushes yes.
Phishing is behind 50-70% of all data breaches. That's the key to
- the most complex crimes we have in the world. It's the email itself ...
According to Statistics Sweden, it was sent to three million Swedes some years ago–
–These types of emails. And I know there are even more.
So it's the crime where you use the power of the internet the most.
It's a simple way to trick a large number of people.
It's enough that a few people falls for it for the people behind to earn-
- an incredible amount. There's a huge amount of money in it.
The plan is to try to infect Kristoffer's laptop with a back door.
A hidden program that gives us remote access to it-
-so we can spy on the user.
But many variables and obstacles make it difficult, and time is short.
To avoid suspicion Jesper pretends he's a photographer.
The goal is to run malicious code on Kristoffer's computer via a USB
- without him noticing.
-Hey! Welcome. -Thanks. I'm Jesper.
I got a camera and pretended like I belonged.
I walked around the room and pretended that I was one of the team.
At the same time I had contact with my colleagues on the outside.
Everyone in Ocean's Thirteen who intends to rob a bank
-But haven't managed to get the blueprints yet, can relax.
Such blueprints have leaked! Who are these hackers?
They are ingenious. We have to work even harder to catch up.
I am a TV host at SVT and host Svenska Nyheter.
I work full time with it 20 weeks a year.
Otherwise, I do podcasts which we record and edit here.
Let's prepare the interview. We'll take a picture when Jesper sits down.
I'll take one in here when it's empty.
When you left and did the interview I was alone in one of the rooms.
There was no door in between. I could have poked him in the neck.
Very close! Not much sound is needed for someone to turn around.
While the team prepares the interview -
- David and Linus drives to Therese's apartment to plant more traps.
- Do you have her address? -No, I actually don't have that.
- Should I fix it? -Yes, do it.
Therese: The worst that can happen is everything that risk my safety.
It only takes one crazy person -
- to make it very uncomfortable for me and my family.
The worst that can happen is private information being spread-
-like phone number and address, and that the wrong person uses it against me.
David is preparing an envelope with her address on–
And a letter with a USB stick, a usb memory.
There's a backdoor on it. It looks like a pdf file but is a backdoor.
We'll drop it in her mailbox.
We trick her to open the file.
We'll say we nominate her for an award–
-Because she's a good influencer and has made a effort.
I'll see if I can attack her wifi.
It could work or completely fail, but here we go.
David and I were waiting outside her gate for someone to enter.
Then the plan was to follow. Two people came -
-Which entered the adjoining gate so then we went in there instead.
It turned out that we got into her staircase via that gate as well.
I have the PIN code for the door, if we want to come back.
The USB stick is delivered. If she pluggs it into the laptop and opens the file-
- then we'll get access to her computer and can steal secrets–
-And maybe access password.
We have recorded signals from the wifi.
If we break the wifi password, we go back.
We're trying as many attack surfaces as possible–
- instead of all the eggs in one basket.
The risk is that it doesn't work. She may not even read the email.
Someone else might handle her emails. A lot can go wrong.
That's why we're throwing a wide net, to increase the chance of success.
We agree that that you should challenge your mandate.
Interesting things happen there, whether you are a host -
-Or if you are the principal of a school.
Challenge what you are allowed to do and consider what you'd rather do–
-And try to squeeze it into your mandate.
It will be much more fun if you do.
What happens will happen. The USB will place files locally-
-But also sends two connections to our server.
Älvsjö. It's running.
-Maybe it's the USB. Yes, yes, yes!
I suspect that my approach to IT security–
- is a bit like people's attitude to safety at sea.
"I don't need a life jacket, because I never go near the edge. "
You're thinking one step too short. If there's a fire, you have to jump overboard.
Then the difference between survival and death is a life jacket.
You don't understand what you're doing But I don't think I'm the worst.
I've still made an effort at some point. I don't want to be the guy who didn't want-
- there to be cars, because horses were safer.
This is how it is.
There is nothing worse than sitting in an internal system -
- like an uncle named Leif has created, which sucks-
-Just to avoid sharing our eating habits -
- with Silicon Valley. Which they will find somewhere anyway.
I can 't do anything about it. Deal with it.
- Is it still open? -Yes.
-Now! -Yes! We're in!
We have access to basically all files, and we're downloading them.
Documents, photos, but above all passwords.
We downloaded everything that may contain passwords, such as browsers.
-Thanks so much. See you tonight. -Yes, we will.
Even if the hackers have access to Kristoffer's computer -
- they need to get the passwords. This is where key chain comes into the picture.
Key chain is an encrypted container where the computer saves passwords
PIN codes and credit card details. For our hackers, it's a goldmine.
The problem is that the lock is robust and hard to crack.
You are currently 1:st in the queue.
People often use the same basis when picking passwords.
It's super common for people to add a year and a special character.
So that he has one of his former known passwords with a year after–
- is something we must try.
Welcome to the Tax Information.
Hi. My name is Linus. I want some information about a person's child.
We'll see what information we have.
It's easy to call the Swedish Tax Agency, it's like an open book.
- Is this about Kristoffer Appelquist? -Yes.
Two adult children and a minor. Want to know who the adults are?
Everyone.
- Was it the addresses you wanted? –Social security numbers.
Something we know is common is to use the children's birthyear.
-Only the first six digits? - No, all of it.
-Great. Thanks so much. -Thanks. Bye.
This is not Denmark, with semi-secret social security numbers.
We guessed passwords like crazy. Pretty slow against an Apple Keychain.
It went slowly. The hours went. We had a deadline of 20:00.
I'm gonna have to stop now. I just don't have enough time.
- Therese? -Yes. It will be difficult.
We've tried to crack her wifi, but failed.
We put a letter with a usb memory in her mailbox.
She hasn't plugged it in it seems. We still have the phishing attack.
I can imagine Therese's day starts with her having her morning coffee.
Then she opens her computer, and there's 56,000 unread emails.
Scroll, scroll. "Let's get to work." I don't think she has time.
Since yesterday I have received text messages which looks different.
It's an sms with asian characters, I don't know what language. And...
And yesterday when I sat on Youtube, I was logged out.
My partner asked: "Does this usually happen?" It has not happened in eight years -
-That I was suddenly logged out of Google and Youtube.
So that was weird.
The hackers realize that there's no time to both steal Therese's password-
–And get past her two-factor- authentication. The hack is canceled.
-Hello. -Hello! Hey!
-How's it going? -Good.
You have on the street met a dad to a fan.
-Yes!.
I was so happy too.
And then I got an email from his daughter and became so happy.
I clicked the link, because she had seen something in a video. I clicked.
What happened then?
It came up that I should fill in my details. So I closed it.
–Ah ... - We sent you phishing emails.
The goal was to get you to click -
-And hopefully, sometime when you're not so alert, log in–
-And then we hope that the details were used elsewhere.
Oh, no! Was it phishing, phishing- email, when you send out links?
-Exactly. "Nätfiske" in Swedish. -I understand.
Very well done, Therese!
This was very unpleasant, but it was very interesting.
I have learned a lot about reflecting.
- Very kind of you, Therese. -Thank you so much for today.
We all need to improve our security on the internet, talk about it.
We need to educate ourselves and each other.
We need to make demands on politicians for major efforts -
- when it comes to our IT security.
They need to give more money to the police–
So that they can investigate and prevent crime on the internet.
These are important issues.
Passwords must be unique. That is the most important thing.
Because if one service gets hacked, you only need to change that password-
- and wont risk something happening on the other sites.
The second is that it must be long - at least 12-15 characters.
The children's names - no. The dog's name or the registration number - no.
123456 - no, come on!
Rather than a character soup you can use a phrase. You can have:
"MyMotherSangForMeOnce- WhenIWasSleeping".
The longer, the harder it is to crack. It is easier to remember phrases.
But we shouldn't have to remember passwords - use password manager!
There are countless of them. find out your needs, and choose tools.
–Hey! Good work! -So damn nice!
The breakthrough came when my computer cracked the password to his key chain.
It was a combination of his old password "hatasj" -
And the birth year of one of his children. Then the treasure chest opened: key chain.
Now we all have passwords in the key chain. We have Chrome login passwords.
We have to decrypt it now, because it contains more passwords.
David managed to decrypt it and the secrets just poured out.
We all have passwords for Chrome Extensions now. Everything!
–The works! –162 different ones. Good.
-We can login to Instagram, right? -What nasty tricks should we do?
-I think a picture is fun. - I can check Facebook.
He has to put up with a bit of mischief.
We take a picture where we stand with a sign: "Double passwords."
Are you ready? Smile.
Ten hours has passed since the hackers infected Kristoffer's computer.
Now Jesper can be himself. It's time to reveal himself.
-Hello! My name is Jesper. -Welcome.
I work as an IT security specialist - you probably already understood that.
-I have. - You look a bit confused.
No, but ... I think we have had contact during the day.
- I got some emails because of you. -That's probably true.
-At least the last few hours. -Right.
- Have you noticed anything else? -I think Instagram, Facebook and ...
- Can we check Instagram now, or? -Yes absolutely.
Damn, you didn't post on Instagram? -No no no....
Check the latest post. Are you nervous, or?
-Yes of course. No worries, it's safe for work.
Do you recognize anyone? / JESPER LAUGHS /
Thank you very much. It says "double passwords".
Proof that I was owned, It hurt little.
I'm not an IT manager at some damn security company.
-I'm a clown. -But a pretty good clown.
But I didn't do this alone, I had help. Here they are.
Can you see us? You're frozen.
-Yes now. Hey! -Hello!
David and I were in the hotel room and joined via Teams.
We could control his computer from there.
- Do you have your computer in front of you? -I do.
Is there something on your screen now?
I opened this document that I had-
- with over 100 usernames and password, on the screen.
–Shit! - You need triple passwords.
Thanks. I knew this would come back and bite me in the ass.
It was fun hacking Kristoffer, since Svenska Nyheter is quite provocative.
He took it well.
But ... oh yeah. It's pretty frustrating, because it's not just my passwords.
It's SVT's password -
-Which I have been given as trade secrets. Damn, this sucks!
But you know? I'm also super happy.
Because if I had this list, I would have save so much time!
I've agreed to this, so not much to whine about.
It's an eye opener how all your stuff is connected.
"I have that password there too, so if someone finds it "...
I get that someone malicious can mess things up for me.
A bit like standing at the board in The Luxury Trap:
"I knew I had bad economy but not that it was this bad. "
Good summary.
The hackers' phishing against Therese failed.
Therese clicked on a link, but never entered her details.
Kristoffer's computer was infected.
The hackers could, after eight hours unlock the computer key chain.
They stole just over 100 credentials, like Kristoffer's Instagram account.
Kristoffer: I was happy to join this program.
The reason is simple: It would be fun to find out what I am worst at–
-So that I can be the best at it instead. Now I can start doing it right.
I searched for passwords. Then I've been reading. You have to kill me now?
-No, but ... Is the camera turned off? - We need to fix this.
What you have found, we have to fix - and it's pretty urgent.
Subtitles: Barbro Garneij Swedish Media Text for SVT