Sweden is very computerized. This creates attack surfaces.
The threat is real.
Not much resources are put into security as would need to.
SVT has hired four professional hackers attack individuals–
and companies, to show how vulnerable we are in our connected society.
The basic functions of society are constantly attacked–
And the results can be catastrophic.
Can our hackers access an important company?
We have received a mission, so we'll run through it.
It's Helsingborgshem.
They have just moved to new premises with "max security".
A brand new building, nice lobby and everything like that.
Helsingborgshem has 1/5 of all residents in Helsingborg.
Businesses, health centers, schools - in addition to ordinary flats.
It's a large part of Helsingborg.
They have asked us to test the security of the building.
We have to get inside and place a computer.
I've already been there.
They have good access systems, so you need cards, possibly code.
There's tall glass doors which closes tightly–
-So it won't be easy to accompany someone inside.
I have checked the entrances. We need to get in via the main entrance.
- During Covid, this becomes hard. - It will be a challenge.
Richard is the IT-manager and security manager at the company.
We have agreed to this because we want to test ourselves.
That is a crucial issue and it is very important to address it.
If we can help others see the importance, then it's great.
The mission is to enter the head office -
and place a computer.
Via the computer we can infiltrate the network and take over:
The register where protected info about the tenants is available–
And housing queue. Can they manipulate the system–
-And put themselves first in line?
For me, it's interesting to see how they do it–
-Because we have not informed staff that this is underway.
No one, except me, knows what we are doing.
I think "social engineering" - part will succeed.
But I do not think the network attack will succeed.
Social manipulation, or "social engineering", means-
- that a hacker exploits someones strong instinct to be social.
We'll send an email to the reception which says-
- that the consultant needs access to a conference room.
It will look like it came from the manager to trick the reception.
Linus has registered a domain that is identical to Helsingborgshems.
"L" is replaced by a capital "i".
It's impossible to see if the mail comes from the real IT-manager.
15 minutes before David arrives at the reception we will send the email.
They won't have time to call people and double check, it should be hectic.
-Let's press "send". -Yes.
–11.32 it was sent. -Here we go.
If David enters a conference room, he can place a minicomputer there.
Then it can call out to our server.
One of the most common ways today is via social engineering.
You look for a person - it can be the receptionist, or support.
Both functions are there to help visitors and customers adjust.
Nor can they question everything.
They need to learn to see through, be suspicious and think:
"Is this really true?"
Hey! My name is David. I was contacted by Richard Mauritsson.
With a tool bag, or delivery or whatever–
-You often come in in many places.
Welcome!
Once inside, then you are inside the shell.
And inside anything can happen.
I'm going to call him.
He has sent an email and has booked a conference room for me.
He said he had contacted you. You should have an email.
He has cc:ed me.
A larger company in Sweden discovered by chance
- they had a server that was not theirs.
That you can trick your way in via "social engineering" .....
One manipulates, says that you have an important errand –
- it happens all the time.
He said to me that he would be busy today.
I can't talk about it, but there has been an incident.
The issue is that it's internal –
-So everyone may not have been informed.
I can't really tell you.
So I get it, I was woken up this morning too. Hope you understand.
She looks at the email, at me–
- then they close the door and start talking to each other.
"Now I'm fucked, now I'm done."
The receptionist called me, who was a little unsure about a man–
-Who wanted a conference room. She wondered, "Should I let him inside?"
Because I had not sent an email I also became suspicious.
I did not know if it was SVT. It could be a confused consultant.
- You'll have to call Richard. -Perfect. I'm calling from here?
I'm taking one last chance.
If she's just listening to my tone that I am nervous or insecure–
- She'll throw me out. I say, "Hey!, it's David. I'm here. "
She doesn't know Richard's reply.
I'm a colleague of Linus Kvarnhammar.
Our receptionist was exemplary. She was insecure and contacted me.
I am very happy and very proud of that our staff has that insight.
Thanks.
It was "game over", we were "busted".
She called Richard immediately. He did not answer.
She called, called, then he picked up.
Shame. That's how it is.
It feels like a huge failure.
To have planned something so well, the adrenaline pumps  ...
And we didn't succeed.
Their new office feels thought out and hard to access.
They have thought about the physical security.
We had to regroup, me and Linus, and think differently.
When we were going to the new building, there were two addresses.
The new address, and an old one.
Helsingborgshem has two. We have been to one.
The other is at on Drottninggatan out by the bathing area.
Then we saw that it existed another office that may be alive.
- We'll go there then. I'm lost.
We'll see when we arrive. this rundown building.
Lights are off, it's dark.
It said that the office has moved.
- They're at Drottninghög. -They have moved? Thanks.
It seemed totally dead, initially.
-No wireless networks? -We checked if there was wifi.
Yes, here. One unprotected network.
I find an open network called Helsingborgshem–
And a closed one called Hbghem. Here's a lot of stuff.
When we sit there and hack, we see a person enter the building.
It wasn't totally dead then. So maybe it's possible to get in.
A person is coming.
It only takes a minute. It looks as if someone is entering the building.
So I went with her. She looked who I was and walked in a door.
- Did you see if she went up or down? -She went into a room here.
We Swedes are SO afraid of conflict.
We glance a little. "But what if someone is new?"
We dare not say, "What are you doing here?" It's something you have to do.
If you see someone you don't recognize, ask.
Wait a minute, another car is coming. Can you shut yourself in?
-Where are you now? -I'm in a storeroom.
The so-called caretaker is probably on his way in now–
- so be quiet and hope that that person goes upstairs.
Don't move. The person enters ... now.
I was looking for a place to plug our minicomputer into.
There were empty offices, some with handbags.
So I took one of the most empty, crawled down on the floor–
-Plugged it in and the network cable–
- and waited for a light to come on that shows there is network traffic.
No, I'm not getting a link.
Anticlimax. Could they have closed the network here?
But then it hit me that there was a reception.
And there was network equipment there. "What if those outlets are active?"
There I connected the small computer.
And the light began to shine.
"we could be done now. But I want to get it confirmed from the outside. "
I'm inside Helsingborgshem. Can you open your laptop quickly?
I have no way to verify that it works.
I just want to check that it has connected and then escape.
Then I hear voices outside.
A meeting room has been emptied of people who are standing outside.
And I have Jesper on the phone, to check if the computer is alive.
People outside are standing and talking. I have not locked the toilet door -
-So someone might open and go inside. and I'm standing there with a phone.
Jesper says: "Boom, looking really good. We are indeed in. "
"Found a domain controller. Good. We're really in. "
Yes!
We are on the right network. You have to try to get out now.
He can 't be there anymore, so he decides to play it super cool.
He flushes the toilet, opens the door and just walks out.
Opened and went out as if I belonged there. Turned my back to the people.
I don't even know if they saw me.
When I noticed that no one followed -
- was a really good feeling.
Now we have a wonderful time of hacking on the internal network in front of us.
Attacks on companies with important functions–
-Can have serious consequences.
One afternoon in February the sodium hydroxide levels rose at the
-waterworks in Oldsmar in Florida, USA.
Hackers had gotten into the system that controlled the plant.
A discharge of sodium lye in the water–
- could have led to catastrophic consequences.
Luckily an employee had the situation under control
-And lowered the levels again.
In May, long queues formed at gas stations on the east coast of USA.
The oil company Colonial's pipeline–
-Had been taken over by hackers which stopped oil supplies.
And in September last year a patient died
-When the hospital in Düsseldorf had been attacked by hackers–
- which made it impossible to receive patients.
An ambulance had to drive to a hospital in Wuppertal.
But when it arrived, it was too late. The patient had died.
These are just a few examples on cyberattacks–
- against important societal functions.
- Here come the hackers! - This is Jinny.
Jinny joined for the first time physically. Awesome.
She's an awesome hacker. It's going to be great.
- We have to go through everything. -What's our goal?
- We'll divide our tasks. - A wonderful, disorganized atmosphere.
You and I, Jesper, start mapping up the network.
Linus, you'll look at AD.
-David tried to organize the chaos. -I'll look at host discovery.
Jesper just wants to go in and attack everything and hack, super eager.
Let's not be too hasty and think that we ...
False "assumptions" can lead us into a "rabbit hole".
Then we started letting loose in four different ways.
You had a list. A combo list, or what have you found?
-You found it with leaked passwords. -Yes, but I haven't tried them.
Often when you start a test like this on a larger network -
-It's pretty chaotic. It's nice to be able to work unstructured.
They use Telia as an ISP at least.
Do you have the port scan results?
It's on Dropbox, in the recon folder.
Our mini-computer tricks computers to connect to us instead.
You can trick them to send secrets -
-Which you can crack if the password is bad.
Install wireguard tools, then you get a daemon
-Oh, what's this? -That's a ...
Take user once.
Rava, then. This feels very PLC.
Careful now.
We tricked a computer to give us a secret which we cracked pretty quickly.
Now you're toast, Richard! Soon.
Now, cracked.
No - Administrator!
Kerberoast is up and running. It took a few seconds–
- then we got a hit on the Administrator account.
The administrator has access to all machines on a network.
There is a group of such users at all companies.
I'm testing the password against the domain controller.
If it is green, the password works.
If it's yellow, then we're domain admin and own the entire network.
–Boom! -Yes!.
It was a "game over scenario".
That was their domain administrator account.
So this user was the key to the kingdom.
- The housing queue is ours. -I'm in the queue, can we promote ...
-Yes of course. -I have already registered.
18.40, then it's "game over time".
Here's a list of all accounts in the entire organization - 850.
And here we have hashed secret, encrypted passwords.
To get them in plain text, we need guess at immense speed.
I'm going to do that with a script. Now it will start working like crazy.
Then we will get a file called "cracked".
There we get a lot of passwords in clear text, which will grow over time.
Now it's been a few minutes. We have cracked 78 passwords.
"Gris1234" (Pig1234).
"Vinter21" (Winter21).
Shall we run a bett on how many contains summer and year?
The most common passwords contain "summer" or "winter" and year.
These are all intercoms and all codes for all properties.
- Inside this system? -Yes.
So what code do you want, to which house?
If you want, then you enter Helsingborgshem.
I'm almost sure that they have gotten in.
As an IT-manager, I have to make it as hard as possible-
-So that the attacker might choose another target.
After a bit of sleep and a lot of adrenaline we would present our findings.
- Can we come in? –Absolutely.
We had bought flowers to the receptionist–
-Who did a good job, because we were thrown out.
I am interested, regardless of the result.
It can give me an answer that means that I can put a new strategy -
- regardless of whether you succeed or fail.
So we got to enter this fort-
- which we did not manage to break into, at least not physically.
We had an envelope to show poor Richard.
Exciting.
An envelope with a password that we cracked. 120, I think it was.
The last page is perhaps the most interesting.
Really interesting.
On the last page, were the admin accounts. Six passwords that we cracked.
He got to see a lot of passwords in plain text.
It may be surprising how bad some are.
Passwords are easy to crack. It doesn't matter where you work.
People should remember their password.
You try to find a password that works.
He gets a few pages with usernames and passwords you don't want.
The password quality maybe wasn't fantastic.
The first thing that many think of When discuss IT is technology.
"We have to get this, and that, computers and technology. "
While in fact it's knowledge, consciousness–
Rules and guidelines, which are important.
It's 80 percent consciousness, knowledge, guidelines and routines -
And 20 percent technology.
We'll change password policy -
- where we won't change passwords so often, and require longer passwords.
Hopefully we can get people to use better passwords.
He was looking for his own name in the list of cracked passwords -
-But we haven't cracked it, so it's a compliment to him.
To find your own password there, would not have been great.
Then I'd have to rethink.
But it didn't end there. We showed him what one can accomplish.
If you look at this, do you recognize this?
I think it's one of our phase 2 servers.
-What is that? -Our real estate system.
It's our customer register and our housing queue.
- Do you think we got it? -Yes, because you have the interface up.
It was like a small joke.
As we established access, Linus was already a customer.
But he did not have many points in the housing queue.
Now we could actually give Linus 1337 points–
-But we held back.
So now we have reached our goals.
Their mission was to enter the network.
And then access the customer register and manipulate the housing queue.
The hackers never succeeded physically to enter the head office -
-But via an old office they got the access.
The hackers needed less than four hours to take over the network.
They managed to get the customer register and manipulate the housing queue.
The way your hackers entered the housing company–
-Will work in over 90 percent of cases.
There is no company in the world which one can not get into.
If these really skilled people want to get in, they will.
They have done this in less than 48 hours, and even less than that.
of course you are impressed of how quietly they have done this.
We had all the power to do what we wanted. That's pretty serious.
The Coop food chain had to close almost all its 800 stores in the country.
- Crime has moved online. - It's up. Yes, we have contact!
Yes!
We're going to stop somewhere. It feels as if I have done something bad.
This is extremely serious.
Subtitles: Anders Kaage Swedish Media Text for SVT