/ ALARM /
Good morning, Klara. Hope you have slept well.
It is sunny outside. The temperature is 7 degrees and it's quite windy.
Good morning, Molly. Hope you have slept well.
It's Tuesday. Don't forget, Molly has outdoor activities-
-and that Klara should bring homework to school.
Start the coffee maker.
Sure. Setting it on level two.
Our homes are becoming increasingly connected and filled with smart devices.
Features such as locks, alarms and - security are today connected to the Internet.
And all digital systems has flaws.
More and more home equipment is connected to the network.
All this is hacked easily, which the criminals know.
We will test
if our hackers can take control over a connected home.
-They have 30 hours. -I think we have to steal one.
What do you want me to do?
My name is Karl-Johan Lidenalv and work as a system manager within IoT.
IoT means "internet of things" -
-and means connected machines and things.
That is a basic precondition to control the home
-without human interaction.
What will the weather be like?
In Karlskrona it will be mostly sunny.
Temperatures of 2-16 degrees.
Our morning routine is based on that we should easily get out of bed in time.
We raise curtains, and turn on the light during the winter.
We start the radio. Everything to get a awakening as possible.
Then our assistant informs us what is happening today.
Let me talk to the store.
Hey! Already back? What can I do for you?
Add pear drink to shopping list.
-Roger. What more do you need? -Candy.
-Okay. Hope to hear from you soon. -It will probably be added on Saturday.
The big thing we have is the automations.
But the children probably use the assistants more than us adults, in general.
Best way to Bastasjön by bus is to take the bus 3 which leaves at 7.27-
-from the AWA road that lies 10 seconds from your location.
The journey takes a total of 26 minutes.
I know the goal is to get in and take over my smart home.
But I have not released information and do not know where they'll start.
The smart home consists of about 70 microprocessors and sensors
- in the house and the backyard. Karl-Johan works from home
-but has poor view of the garden and backyard, where the hackers are.
Now the hackers have to find a sensor without Karl-Johan discovering it.
-Found something? -Yes and no.
-Was there anything that felt connected? -There's a sensor.
Is the guy an old soldier? There might be mines buried.
We can be burglars. Dibs for not being that.
-Are they home? -There are people at home.
I don't know what we're doing yet, but we're hacking a house with a gentleman-
-who has lots of connected tiny computers that controls different things.
We need to access his sensors in the garden.
They may contain secrets, so that we can connect to the inside.
If anyone wonders what I'm doing there-
-I'll pretend to be from land inspection or an estate agent.
Some kind of office worker, because that's how I'm dressed.
Our plan is to follow cables in the– backyard that can lead to sensors.
-Hey! Did you get it? - Get this!
There's a fucking router here, so we can connect directly to it.
He went in as a burglar and scouted.
He probably found what we were looking for.
A box that probably has a control unit to the stuff we want to hack.
But he also found a router and power.
So really, we can just connect here like a network unit.
Pretty sure I'm safe. They will never get in.
Should they, against all odds, get in, they can't take over my smart home.
This is the time they lose.
Here we have the router which is the entrance to the network.
Everything is built together and integrated with each other.
If you want to get in, this is it.
It's the heart of my smart home and the most sensitive machine.
Here you see when someone has logged in to the router. It's me, hopefully.
More and more home equipment is connected to the network.
The lawnmower, your alarm or your baby monitor.
Everything is connected. Even the fridge.
All this is hacked easily,
-since most companies use the same passwords for the entire series of products.
which the criminals know. -And then take over.
You can turn off the alarm remotely in your home, if it is of that type.
Yes, we are in a 2.10-network. Now we have access to the inside.
We have found a router on the outside which we have plugged into.
It has a bad connection towards the rest of the house-
-but we have validated that it is the correct network, so we reach devices in the house.
-Check quickly and map up the inside. -It's slow, but I'm doing it.
Then we'll work from that.
I think I have somewhat higher security thinking than the average user.
I have a real firewall, or a real router with a firewall in.
I have my IoT devices segregated on their own network.
So even if you take over the IoT devices they can't take over my smart home.
I have rules in the firewall that locks people out who behave badly.
- Do you see the access point? -No, there's nothing.
-I don't see anything either. -Have they turned it off?
The network disappeared for a bit-
-so we think someone pulled the cord to the brain. Which is bad.
We no longer have access. The guy was probably paranoid and pulled out the cord.
We do not see wifi anymore.
The hackers have lost contact and need to find access.
Jesper wants to steal one of the houses microprocessors. The clock is ticking...
We need to steal a device to see how they are configured.
-You get a pair of pliers. - Shall we cut it off?
We take the configuration to the hotel-
and make a hacker button during the night.
Then we can press Enter tomorrow.
That's as non-technical I can make it.
You're not filming this, are you? We'll just go and take that shit down.
A small circuit board on the different sensors that contain secrets
-which we want to extract. We need them physically.
I'll find a "Raspberry Pi" and remove the memory card from it.
And Jesper will find the sensor.
The car is also connected, which it wasn't from the beginning.
I have put in a gps tracker in my automation layer.
I load the car's position-
-and when the car comes home, the garage door open.
Jesper.
What's up? Had a good day? - Did you have a good day as well?
-Did you check that the power did not die? -Yes.
Now we have access to one of the networks
-and can try to get further in via that one.
We often have consumer products that are wide open to a hacker.
It is a danger in several different ways. We can be monitored.
Pictures and information can get into the wrong hands.
An example is watches you have for monitoring children and where they should go.
From them others have obtained that information.
It's uncomfortable if anyone else knows where all the children are.
It can also affect our society.
You then connect many IoT things, for example cameras, in a huge network.
Then you use them to attack for example authorities and newspapers.
Through your router criminals can take over Internet-connected objects.
They can order thousands of devices in thousands of homes-
-to send requests at the same time to a company or an authority.
A so-called DDos attack.
The company's system is blocked, and they can not perform normal tasks.
All this happens in silence without you having an idea of what's going on.
You can buy a network of computers in e.g. Russia-
-and pay per hour, as long as you are going to use it.
- Do you want some food? -Yes! We'll put it here.
Nothing has affected my work-
-but I have noticed that unknown devices has accessed our wifi.
A switch stopped working at 13.55.
I'm a little nervous, I must say.
-Why didn't it say anything about the laundry? -30 degree washes do not go to 100%.
They only go to 99%, and then it does not have time to react.
My wife...
-I'm interested when it works. -It always does.
I can't turn on a lamp without using the phone.
I can't pull up the blinds anymore, the strings are removed.
I remember there was a weekend ...
... when it was dark, cold and winter, and something went down.
All weekend I could not turn on the lights. He wasn't very popular then.
When the garage door went up and down at night she wasn't happy.
If I said it was annoying to go and see if the laundry was finished
-he'd reply: "I'll fix it!" We have a speaker that says:
"The washing machine is ready, the hot tub is hot ... "
We connect it and record a sound.
A lamp turns green when it's finished and red when it's not.
The washing machine is ready.
-The... -It's green now, so it's done.
It turns green during the second half.
-Is it finished, then? -I heard it.
My wife is not entirely positive.
She thinks I'm a nerd and that I do it for my own sake.
But it's happiness those times that I make her think-
-that I've done good stuff.
The dryer is ready.
Let me talk to the store. Do you have a recipe for gratin?
-ICA is unfortunately not answering right now. -Do you have a recipe?
But Dad, Mom knows, so ask her.
Yes, then we'll try it. - Hi mom...!
Add margarine to the shopping list.
Add fruit to the shopping list.
Add salad to the shopping list.
The hackers go to the hotel to work undisturbed.
They notice that Karl-Johan's system is more advanced than they hoped for.
This IoT man is like a mad scientist.
there are firewalls and network segmentation.
So different networks for the different devices. There are different accounts.
He's really thought of everything. It's super hard to hack him.
We're trying to learn to speak "curtain language".
We don't know what language they speak, and therefore they do not understand us.
We can send data to them, however they're sitting there in the window and like:
"What? No."
There are a number of networks. We have access to two of them.
Inside are all the units which we want to control.
But we don't know how to control them - how the pool and blinds are controlled.
We have to log in to the other network where the "levers" are located.
We have tools, but no levers.
It's a sharp learning curve because no one has done it before.
What the fuck?
It just stopped working. It's very strange.
Have we said we can handle this? We're told you we'd give it a try.
-This... -Oh, how frustrating.
We want to trick the devices on the network to talk to our unit-
-so that we can record all traffic.
We hope that they then send important information.
We want to record when a device sends "lower the blinds".
If we catch this "request", we can replay it and do the same.
Then we'll learn how it works.
Now we've been sitting all day, tonight and quite late at night.
Jesper has given up. He couldn't bear it and needed to sleep.
The sound engineer and others from the film crew has given up.
Jinny and I are left and we have to crack this.
But we'll see because it's quite late at night.
I've found some interesting stuff.
Three new machines which we have not connected to.
David has created an account that has synced to the different devices.
We have now logged on to more devices.
We are administrators on the entire network.
Imagine we are here, and so we find a small path into the third network.
But we have not found the net that controls the devices.
The plan now is to try to get in on the "mother server" that controls everything.
From there, we can control all devices instead of going to each device.
Instead of talking "blinds" we are trying to talk "mom" -
-and then mom gets to talk blinds.
If we can learn how to do that, we get access to everything.
I've probably found the brain. Here is the "input number curtain bedroom".
We are not far from it now.
Shall we connect a hotspot and just go from there?
So sick! We'll do it again.
-Radio: If I could ... -Fuck, that scared me!
-Why did it start? -Press...
Okay...
We can't count our chickens yet. We've only opened the garage door.
So now we're scheming, because we want to see what we can do.
Can we control the washing machine, the pool, the curtains and Spotify?
We want to take over everything in the whole house.
We think that we can speak these languages-
-and then we build a giant program which turns everything on.
It's going to be awesome if it works.
Damn, good job yesterday! I didn't have any energy left. You're awesome.
-I felt I couldn't give up. -Good.
-Check Keybase. -We want him to notice us.
I'll call you soon. I'll sneak around a bit.
You're online.
-I've started Spotify in Klara's room. -I was going to take the kitchen.
Do it. I'm running the death script now.
It's running.
-Run it in the kitchen too. -Let's go.
- "Epic Sax Guy". -Absolutely.
It's not that dangerously annoying ...
Let's turn up the volume.
Now it's "saxophone guy".
The garage door opens.
-Turn off. - It's not us.
They have hacked our home.
They lower a little now and then.
They're lowering. Damn. They lower, but I raise.
The garage door closes.
You can lower a little. It's very loud in there.
I've lowered now.
It was a bit disappointing.
I understood that they had gotten in and taken over the home.
"Guilty as charged."
Come, let me show you something. You're a hero.
My God, how many units do you have! A big compliment, then.
-Good work. You have succeeded. -Not without us pulling our hair.
-It was quite a struggle. -Shit, you have so much stuff. Cool.
I didn't think they would get in.
The biggest discomfort came when I saw devices online on my wifi
-which is not my IoT wifi. Then I felt that the battle was lost.
Yesterday we were here and connected on the Olympus network.
We had "access tokens" and everything, and could talk to your "home assistant".
We opened the garage door and lit a lamp somewhere in the house.
Was it opened last night? I didn't notice that.
Yesterday I felt very confident that they wouldn't come any further.
But I was wrong, and they got in.
The hackers gained a foothold in the smart home network.
They gained access and hacked the net that controlled all IoT devices.
From this position
Suppliers must deliver safe products
-and have certification or labeling.
Everyone in Sweden will never be IT security experts.
However, we understand if there is a safety label on a product.
We need to protect our homes, so if you have everything connected
-not only the router but everything else, then you should have a secure password.
Otherwise, the bad guys will enter your home, no matter how much you lock.
Check this out! Logged in as AppleStoffe.
You change a number in the password.
I really understand that it's not perfect.
We're going to hack Therése Lindgren and take over her online identity.
Subtitles: Karin Hellstadius Swedish Media Text for SVT